

SUBHADEEP SEN DATA ENTHUSIAST | SENIOR CONSULTANT

EVERBODY LOVES A NICE STORY. I TELL MINE WITH DATA!!

CONTACT INFO

- (+91)-908-353-1573
- <u>subhadeep.sen@outlook.in</u>
- <u>www.linkedin.com/me</u>
- Kolkata, West Bengal, India

EDUCATION

2012-2016

Bachelor of Technology Heritage Institute Of Technology, Kolkata

2005-2012

Secondary and Higher Secondary Ramakrishna Mission Vidyapith, Purulia

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- PySpark
- Python
- Amazon Redshift
- Databricks
- AWS Athena, AWS Glue
- AWS Lambda, EC2
- Apache Airflow
- Docker
- O SQL

DOMAIN

- Insurance
- TeleCommunication

PERSONAL DETAILS

- - Date Of Birth: Nov 28, 1994
- Sex: Male
- Nationality: Indian

ABOUT ME

I am a Data enthusiast looking forward to work in a stimulating environment, where I can implement and enhance my skills and knowledge to meet both organizational and individual goals. Team player with strong desires to face new challenges and expand my skills set.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2022 - PRESENT

CURRENT ORGANIZATION

Ernst & Young Global Delivery Service India

ERNST & YOUNG GLOBAL DELIVERY SERVICE INDIA OCT 2022 - PRESENT

CLOUD DATA ENGINEER

Worked as a Cloud Data Engineer, leading the Transfromation Team in migrating the Claims from the legacy claim system into the strategic EIS system. Worked in setting up the AWS Infrastructure for endto-end data pipeline using AWS s3, Glue, Athena and AWS Managed Services (Apache Airflow). Developed the customized transfromation framework in Python, deployed as an AWS Glue Job. Developed Airflow DAGs for overall orchestration of the pipeline. Created Technical documentation in Confluence and developer stories in JIRA.

SERVICES LIMITED

JAN 2021 - OCT 2022

TATA CONSULTANCY DATA ENGINEER - PYSPARK

Worked as Data Engineer for migrating existing Microsoft SQL Server database and its dependencies to a centralized repository in AWS. Debugged the existing SSIS packages and re-engineered the code in Pyspark. Developed Spark applications using Pyspark, Spark-SQL for data extraction, for analysizing and transforming data to uncover insights into product analytics and customer usage patterns. Developed Glue Crawler and Jobs for loading the data to corresponding tables in Athena for downstream systems. Experience in creating docker file, building docker images. Responsible for estimating the cluster size, monitoring and troubleshooting of the spark

TATA CONSULTANCY DATA ENGINEER - PYTHON

databricks cluster.

SERVICES LIMITED

DEC 2019 - DEC 2020

Worked as Python and AWS expert for developing customized python framework to automate back-end data preparation for BI Dashboard. Developed User-Defined functions (UDF) and scripts to interact with AWS s3,uploading data to s3 bucket, unloading data from AWS s3 to Amazon Redshift tables. Developed validation and syncing scripts to auto-sync updated data to BI dashboard and refresh.

SERVICES LIMITED

TATA CONSULTANCY BACK-END DEVELOPER & ANALYST

DEC 2018 - NOV 2019

Worked as Amazon Redshift expert to design advanced Redshift Tables, developed optimized queries to manage large volume of data and generate back-end data for Analytical Reports of BI dashboard hosted in ec2 instance.

SERVICES LIMITED

TATA CONSULTANCY SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

APR 2017 - NOV 2018

Member of the development Team for developing a Data Ware House for Client using SQL

PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS

Overall 6+ years of IT experience with 4 years of experience as Data Engineer.Proficient in Analyzing User requirement and functional specifications. Well versed in Exploratory Data Analysis, developing Data pipeline and providing data solutions. Proficient in working with multiple AWS Cloud technologies. Team Player with excellent communication skills.

♣ PY-SPARK

Understanding of Spark framework, big data architectures and developing Data Pipeline.

Strong Experience in data engineering and building ETL pipelines on batch and streaming data using Pyspark, SparkSQL.

Working Experience with large volume of datasets

Good working exposure on Cloud technolgies of AWS - S3, EC2, Lambda, Glue, Athena.

A PYTHON

Experienced with core Python programming, developing customized scripts for automation, developing UDF (user-defined functions), ORMs(Object-Relational Mappers)

Used Python to develop customized framework to interact with AWS s3, Amazon Redshift for preparation of data on cloud. Experience in Python libraries - Numpy, Pandas, boto3.

AMAZON REDSHIFT

Understanding of Amazon Redshift Architecture and hands on experience in developing advanced Tables and optimizing complex Queries in Amazon Redshift

Used materialized view and optimizing techniques of Redshift for dealing with large volume of data and faster report loading